# Panagiotis (Panos) Triantafyllidis

Graduate of Business and IT currently studying MSc in Computer Science, with the target of acquiring employment in the fields of software development, security, and IT after graduation. Background includes independent external study for the development of software skills, strong experience with group projects of academic and professional nature, and a military service utilised under the IT department.

## **EMPLOYMENT & WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Sep 2022 - Sep 2023 | IT and Security assistant

Hellenic Airforce, Athens, Greece

- Part of military service in Greece.
- Experience includes technical support at the IT department of the Hellenic Airforce, Insight into Information Security, and tasks on Web development with React, HTML/CSS/JavaScript.

#### Sep 2020 - May 2021 | Operations and IT Intern

Skywalk Transport and Logistics, Athens, Greece

Work Placement in a transport and logistics company, dealing with B2B deliveries. Assisting in daily tasks which included.

- Auditing 2 ERP systems for parcel/order/vehicle management.
- Gathering order statements and weekly reports.
- Gained insight in database maintenance and website development with React and HTLM/CSS/JS.
- Office Technical support.
- Implementation of self made calculator program made in Visual Basic, assisting report creation and data visualisation.
- Implementation an Access database program, which automated and simplified management of information and report generation.

# Aug 2017 - Aug 2018 | Sales Assistant

"Virus" Men's wear retail store, Megara, Greece

Part time job, in the field of retail business. Experience gained was based on HTML, data management, marketing, and VBA/MSOffice.

# **EDUCATION**

Sep 2023 – Sep 2024 | M.Sc. Advanced Computer Science – Cyber Security focus

University of Manchester, UK

# **Currently in progress**

Sep 2018 – Jun 2022 | B.Sc. Business Computing and Information Technology

Aston University, Birmingham, UK

# Graduated with First Class Honours

- Key Modules: Database Applications [SQL, MSAccess] (79.6%), Applications Development [VisualBasic, C++] (82%), Systems Analysis (78%), Information Security (81%), Project Delivery (76%), BCIT Research project[Supply Chain] (78%).
- Vice President of the Aston Bright Futures Society, the largest network of university societies with professional content in the UK.
- Higher Education Achievement Report provided upon request.

# Sep 2017 – Jun 2018 | Foundation Year Focus on Business and IT

**Network Foundation School, Athens, Greece** 

Overall, Mark:80% (AAB).

- Key Modules: Computing 83%, Statistics 85%, Business and Economics 85%, Project Development 80% [research and large audience group presentation], Programming [C++, Python] 80%.
- Gained experience in presentations upon large audience, understanding the principles of group work, research and time management, through numerous academic assignments.

Sep 2015 – Jun 2018 | N2nd Lyceum, Argyroupolis, Athens, Greece

General Lyceum Apolyterium, GPA of graduation 'Excellent' 18.9/20.0.

## SEMINARS AND TRAINING

#### During my millitary service, I:

- Completed one semester at the University of Athens, on Web Development with focus on HTML/CSS/JS, React16, Angular and Vue.jr, with Certification. [5-month course].
- Completed on semester at Economic University of Athens, on in depth Java programming and database connectivity, with Certification. [5-month course 10 ECTS points].

#### HOBBIES AND SKILLS

- Hobbies include experimentation and studying about Ethical hacking, including CaptureTheFlag and HackTheBox material, while searching for event opportunities to improve technical skills in practise. Currently taking courses from the HtB.academy.com on Linux and Red Teaming.
- Bright Futures Society, Vice President, developed communication and time management skills along with group projects, through the process of conducting weekly events that connected students and employers.
- Student Course Representative, Member of the representative group of Business Computing and IT. Such an opportunity was crucial to conduct research and development for course improvement, and propos module-specific suggestions, which directly influenced the degree experience.

#### IT:

- Intermediate knowledge in Python/C++/Visual Basic/SQL/JavaScript/HTML/CSS.
- Knowledge and understanding of Agile/Waterfall project development from the courses of Systems Analysis (learned in theory) and Applications Development (applied in practice).

#### Languages:

- Native: Greek.
- Fluent: English (IELTS Band score [7] in 2018), Studied for 5 years in England 2018-2022 and 2023-2024.
- Beginner/B1: German.

EU Driving Licence (GREEK): since August 2018.